Register of the Graham C. Dorsett photograph collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Graham C. Dorsett photograph collection
circa 1939-1964
64017
Dorsett, Graham C., collector.
33 envelopes, 2576 prints (3.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Depicts India during and after World War II, the Indian Army in East Africa and Italian East Africa, Indian Independence Day, India's Republic Day, and Indian Navy Day, 1954, ceremonies. Includes prints of Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Indira Gandhi, Krishna Menon, Sukarno, Tito, the Shah of Iran, and Lord and Lady Mountbatten.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1964
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Depicts India during and after World War II, the Indian Army in East Africa and Italian East Africa, Indian Independence Day, India's Republic Day, and Indian Navy Day, 1954, ceremonies. Includes prints of Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Indira Gandhi, Krishna Menon, Sukarno, Tito, the Shah of Iran, and Lord and Lady Mountbatten.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Gandhi, Indira, 1917- --Pictorial works.; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948--Pictorial works.; Krishna Menon, V. K. (Vengalil Krishnan), 1897-1947--Pictorial works.; Mohammed Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, 1919- --Pictorial works.; Mountbatten, Louis Mountbatten, Earl, 1900-1979--Pictorial works.; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964--Pictorial works.; Soekarno, 1901-1970--Pictorial works.; Tito, Josip Broz, 1892-1980--Pictorial works.; World War, 1939-1945--India--Pictorial works.; World War, 1939-1945--Pictorial works.; India--Pictorial works.
Collection Contents
- 31 prints depicting typical Indian women and men., undated (Box 64017 - 10.A-V, Folder A)
- 83 prints depicting Indian workers in various trades and handicrafts, including Jaipur brass artifacts; magistrates in court house; doctors and nurses in hospital wards., undated (Folder B)
- 20 prints relating to education India and depicting schoolboys with their teachers, and students at college., undated (Folder C)
- 63 prints relating to farm life and work in the fields, as well as to life in the city, in India., undated (Folder D)
- 73 prints depicting Indian dances and festivities, including prints of men-gymnasts and wrestlers., undated (Folder E)
- 41 prints relating to animal life in India, with prints of elephants, tigers, bulls, cocks, camels, monkeys, horses and a cat., undated (Folder F)
- 76 prints of governmental and administrative buildings, including an airport and railway stations, as well as aerial views of ruins and barracks, in India., undated (Folder G)
- 122 prints of various Indian monuments, temples, palaces, forts, ruins, including prints of New Delhi, Bombay, the Taj Mahal., undated (Folder H)
- 31 prints of world major cities and tourist attractions, including prints of Katmandu, Singapore, New York, Rome, Florence., undated (Folder I)
- 29 prints of general views of India, including prints of fishing and sailing boats., undated (Folder J)
- 88 prints relating to Republic Day ceremonies in New Delhi including prints of President Prasad, Jawaharlal Nehru, Rajagopal Achari, Mr. and Mrs. Sukarno., January 26, 1950 (Folder K)
- 42 prints of the following Indian political leaders: Jawaharlal Nehru (1889-1964), first Prime Minister of India, including prints with his daughter Indira Gandhi, and President Prasad; Rajendra Prasad (1884-1964), first President of Republic of India; Rajagopal Achari, Governor General of India (1948-1950); Shri Morarji Desai, Chief Minister of India. (Folder L)
- 43 prints of Lady Mountbatten, and Lord Mountbatten, First Earl Mountbatten of Burma; British naval and military leader; viceroy of India (1947), Governor General of India (1947-1948) during their official trip to India, including prints taken with J. Nehru. (Folder M)
- 61 prints of Soraya and Mohammed Reza Pahlavi, (Shah of Iran (1941- ), during their official trip to India, including prints with Nehru, Prasad, Lord and Lady Mountbatten., undated (Folder N)
- 85 prints of Indian personalities, including prints with foreign personalities., undated (Folder O)
- 62 prints of British personalities in India., undated (Folder P)
- 178 prints relating to the British Army in India, including prints of recruiting and training of soldiers; troops at attention and in barracks; soldiers learning various handicrafts, officers and soldiers; aerial views of a military school and training; military parades., undated (Folder Q-R)
- 77 prints relating to the Navy in India, including prints of marines on board; officers; gymnasts; parades; ships, undated (Folder S)
- 99 prints relating to the I.N.S Mysore ceremonies in Bombay, late 1950's, when the I.N.S Mysore became the new Flagship of the Indian Navy, including prints of Krishna Menon (Folder T)
- 95 prints of general views of Italian Eastern Africa, taken in early 1941 during the British offensive., undated (Folder U)
- 102 prints depicting natives, habitats, bazaars of Italian Eastern Africa., about 1941 (Folder V)
- 30 prints relating to military training and operations on the field of the British army in Italian Eastern Africa, Early 1941 (Folder W-Y)
- 394 prints depicting officers and soldiers at camp in Italian Eastern Africa, including prints of General De Gaulle reviewing French troops., Early 1941 (Folder Z-BB)
- 71 prints of wrecked airplanes, tanks, trucks, ships; ports with ships and smaller boats in Italian Eastern Africa., undated (Folder CC)
- 70 prints of various monuments, churches, forts, Italian administrative and commercial buildings in Italian Eastern Africa, including road signs indicating localities such as Cheren, where the Allies won a major victory over Italy in Eritrea., undated (Folder DD)
- 91 prints depicting the British-Indian troops entering in Cheren; Italian population watching; British officers taking over the Italian government's buildings of Eritrea; surrender of Italian troops and prisoners' camp., undated (Folder EE)
- 31 prints relating to the Red Cross and sanitary activities in Italian Eastern Africa, including prints of a musical show for the soldiers., undated (Folder FF)
- 39 prints: miscellaneous, including prints of official military documents; Gordon's statue; a caricature of Lady Mountbatten; a portrait of Mussolini on a truck; Axis headquarters under a tent., undated (Folder GG)